Ruby (Sattar) Romeu – Educator/Senior Developer Advocate

Yes, Ruby, like the programming language.

I'm a Senior Developer Advocate and a teacher in the Providence area. I'm known for organizing local events to get junior developers together (Rhode Island Codes). Using software development as well as my background in education, my goal is to help others achieve their technical goals and impact the future of tech resource accessibility.





rubysattar@gmail.com

Socials: @RubyDotGif

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Postman, Remote -

Technical Enablement Architect -> Senior Developer Advocate AUG 2021 - Jan 2024

I started in the Solutions Engineering team at Postman as a TEA and worked cross-functionally on multiple product squads. As a TEA, I was responsible for:

- Developing demo environments in our product, using multiple API architectural styles to use during sessions with enterprise customers.
- Producing content for our Learning Management System.
- Designing & Creating scaffolded internal and external product learning content through an educational course
- Implementing technical integrations within demo environments to ensure the latest product features were always ready to demonstrate to customers

After transitioning into the Student Programs team at Postman as a **Sr Dev Advocate**, I was responsible for:

- Managing social media presence for Student Programs by hosting livestreams on Youtube, Twitch, and LinkedIn, targeting students and educators with over 15k impressions in the first 6 months of launch.
- Leading in-person and online workshops + sponsoring hackathons, converting over 2k student viewers per quarter into campus product advocates..
- Preparing student ambassadors in the AEMEA region to lead their own product-led workshops. Supporting the initiatives of over 30 students in the AEMEA region in less than 6 months.
- Developing project-based learning courses to promote the company's vision of API literacy through an LMS (SkillJar).
- Producing written internal and external educational content through Confluence and blog articles.
- Engaging with developer communities at in-person events, in online forums, through Zendesk, and on Discord.

TrueMotion/CMT, Boston - Technical Support Engineer FEB 2021 - AUG 2021

TrueMotion/CMTelematics is a leading smartphone telematics platform. As a TS Engineer, I was responsible for:

- Training and onboarding customers onto the company's program management systems.
- Producing/Maintaining a customer support knowledge base and educational videos.
- Debugging customers' technical issues and documenting the process for internal teams.

TECHNOLOGIES

JSON MongoDB
React AWS
jQuery Node.js
SQL Express.js
CSS/Scss Jenkins
Git Postman
NoSQL Jira

RESTful API's

SKILLS

Cross-industry technology
Teamwork
Leadership
Technical Education Delivery
Communication
Coaching
Live-streaming
Project Management

EDUCATION

Online Certifications -

NOV 2019 - Present

Data Analytics (Google), AWS Cloud Practitioner (Amazon), Technical Writing (LinkedIn), Test-Driven Development (LinkedIn)

Florida International University, Miami — Bachelor's in Elementary Education

- Providing escalated technical and triage support, using an incident response protocol.
- Sustaining Engineering through ongoing releases of configuration changes to the company code base.

Magna Cum Laude, Honors, field research in ed-tech.

MAY 2012 - DECEMBER 2014

STEM ENRG, Boston - Project Manager SEP 2020 - APR 2021

STEM ENRG is a non-profit program for women of color. It provides opportunities to build technical projects for local community organizations. I started as a Mentee and was quickly promoted to Project manager, offering technical support, education, and leadership to a team through an Agile workflow.

General Assembly, Boston - Engineering Fellow JUNE 2020 - SEP 2020

At GA's Software Engineering Immersive program, I received a holistic technical foundation essential for full-stack development.

- Built full-stack applications for teachers and conducted user research for continued iteration.
- Incorporated functionality from 3rd-party APIs to add complexity and nuance.
- Collaborated on teams to build and demo applications in an Agile workflow.
- Problem-solved using industry standard development tools and documentation.

PROJECTS

Postman Student Programs Livestreams — A regular livestream hosted on LinkedIn, Youtube, and Twitch to teach API fundamentals and demonstrate technical solutions to common junior developer challenges.

Enterprise Enablement "Cosmic Courses" — Multiple Reveal.js self-serve learning modules for enterprise customers seeking to understand how to use the Postman API platform. **Apple HIG Updates Video Content** — An educational video sponsored by TrueMotion to inform customers about Human Interface Guidelines changes [post-production video editing software used by TrueMotion's Creative Director]

OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KIPP Academy, Boston - Kindergarten Lead Teacher FEB 2018 - JUNE 2020

KIPP is a mission-driven school where teachers regularly collaborate to ensure students' academic success.

- Led a DEI workshop for a team of 30+ educators and school leaders, resulting in actionable commitments for the school environment
- Designed a K-8 Women's History curriculum with G-Suite tech resources.
- Utilized Tableau to analyze data and inform instruction
- Implemented differentiated intervention instruction to a top-performing class of 25 families during a global pandemic.

The Mildred (Boston Public Schools), Boston - Lead Teacher OCT 2017 - FEB 2018

SFPCC of Harvard, Boston - Lead Teacher AUG 2015 - MAY 2017